barilla.com 2019-10-09

# Privacy Policy | Barilla

## STATEMENT OF PRIVACY

Barilla America, Inc. and its wholly owned subsidiary WASA North America LLC **(collectively "Barilla")** recognizes the importance of protecting your privacy and takes that obligation seriously by meeting or exceeding privacy regulations promulgated under United States law. Barilla also knows that you care about how your usage data, including your name, address, telephone number, e-mail address, and credit card information **("Personal Information")** is used and/or shared. Barilla's sole intent in collecting Personal Information is to balance its legitimate business interests against the reasonable expectations of privacy of its customers. As such, except as provided for under USAGE below, BARILLA DOES NOT SELL, RENT, SWAP OR OTHERWISE DISCLOSE ANY PERSONAL INFORMATION TO THIRD PARTIES THAT ARE NOT EMPLOYED BY OR AFFILIATED WITH BARILLA. Consequently, Barilla adopted this Statement of Privacy to inform Barilla website **(the "Barilla Website")** users how it does collect, store, and use Personal Information. 

### EU-US and/or Swiss-US Data Transfers

Barilla has certified to the Department of Commerce that it adheres to the Privacy Shield Principles. See Barilla’s Privacy Shield Statement [here](https://www.barilla.com/en-us/privacy-shield-statement). You can view WASA North America LLC’s Privacy Shield statement [here](http://www.wasa-usa.com/privacy-shield-statement/). To learn more about Privacy Shield, please visit [www.privacyshield.gov](https://www.privacyshield.gov/).

To enable Barilla to provide you with requested information and process orders, Barilla collects Personal Information from you on various sections of the Barilla Website. In addition, Barilla collects Personal Information when you register with the Barilla Website or when you register for any services, special offers or drawings available on the Barilla Website. Barilla may also collect general statistical information of the Barilla Website's usage (such as your IP address, browser type, originating domain names, access times and referring website addresses). Such information is utilized as provided under USAGE below.

### Privacy policies of third party websites

The Barilla Website may contain hyperlinks to third party websites, and while Barilla makes all reasonable efforts to hyperlink to websites that share our high standards and respect for privacy, Barilla is not responsible for the content or the privacy practices of third party websites. As such, Barilla encourages you to review the privacy statements of websites you choose to link to from the Barilla Website so that you can understand how those websites collect, use and share your information.

### Cookies, third party ad networks

When you enter the Barilla Website, we may store some information, in the form of a "Cookie" or similar file, on your computer. Cookies are small pieces of information stored on your hard drive and not on the Barilla Website. Cookies do not spy on you or otherwise invade your privacy and they cannot invade your hard drive and steal information. Rather, the Barilla Website uses cookies to provide greater continuity to you during your session on the Barilla Website and to help you navigate the Barilla Website as easily as possible.

We may allow third-party companies that use tracking technologies, such as cookies or pixels, to record IP information about users who visit or interact with our website. Our website does not provide any personal information to these third parties. This information allows them to deliver targeted advertisements and gauge their effectiveness. Some of these third-party advertising companies may be advertising networks that are members of the Network Advertising Initiative which offers a single location to opt out of ad targeting from member companies.

### Usage

Barilla uses Personal Information for order fulfillment purposes; for marketing and promotional purposes (for example, offering Barilla Website users the opportunity to receive information, participate in special promotions and acquire Barilla promotional products, e-mail based promotions and marketing whether performed by Barilla or by its business partners and independent contractors); developing enhancements to the Barilla Website; and evaluating Barilla Website usage by analyzing usage data in the aggregate, but not with respect to any individual Barilla Website user.

Additionally, Barilla uses Personal Information to direct e-mail to Barilla Website users who register with the Barilla Website or otherwise provide their e-mail address to Barilla regarding specific promotions, updates and service enhancements, and other appropriate or necessary communications. **BY PROVIDING YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION TO BARILLA YOU ARE EXPRESSLY CONSENTING TO BARILLA'S USE OF YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION FOR ALL OF THE PURPOSES SET FORTH IN THIS PRIVACY POLICY AND FOR ANY OTHER ADDITIONAL PURPOSES THAT MAY BE SET FORTH ON THE BARILLA WEBSITE.**

### Disclosure

Barilla may share and disclose your Personal Information with, or collect or use your Personal Information through, our parent, affiliates, associates, agents, suppliers and such other third parties as Barilla, acting reasonably, may deem necessary for the fulfillment of the purposes noted or where otherwise permitted by law. By retaining the services of Barilla, you have consented to the disclosure of your Personal Information to a third party in the circumstances, or for the purposes, set out in this Privacy Policy, and for any other additional purposes that may be set forth in the Barilla website or contained in any additional terms applicable to the particular goods or services indicated or involved.

Barilla also reserves the right to disclose any personal information about you or your use of the Barilla Website, including its contents, without your prior permission if Barilla has a good faith belief that such action is necessary to: (1) conform to legal requirements or comply with legal process; (2) protect and defend the rights or property of Barilla or its affiliated companies; (3) enforce the terms or use; or (4) act to protect the interests of its users and customers. Barilla's performance of this agreement is subject to existing laws and legal process, and nothing contained in this agreement is in derogation of Barilla's right to comply with governmental, court and law enforcement requests or requirements relating to your use of the Barilla Website or information provided to or gathered by Barilla with respect to such use. Further, Barilla may sell your personal information in a sale of all or substantially all of the assets of Barilla.

Barilla may be required to disclose an individual’s personal information in response to a lawful request by public authorities, including to meet national security or law enforcement requirements.

Barilla’s accountability for personal data that it receives under the Privacy Shield and subsequently transfers to a third party is described in the Privacy Shield Principles. In particular, Barilla remains responsible and liable under the Privacy Shield Principles if third-party agents that it engages to process the personal data on its behalf do so in a manner inconsistent with the Principles, unless Barilla proves that it is not responsible for the event giving rise to the damage.

### Security of personal information

All Personal Information is protected by state of the art and consistently upgraded security technology in an effort to safeguard your Personal Information. Nonetheless, Barilla is not responsible for any breach of its security or for the actions of any third parties that may obtain any Personal Information. Also see our Terms of Use and Notices.

### Removal, review and correction

Barilla Website users may remove their Personal Information from Barilla distribution lists by contacting our Customer Service department. 

Barilla acknowledges that EU and Swiss individuals have the right to access the Personal Information that we maintain about them. An individual who seeks access, or who seeks to correct, amend, or delete inaccurate data, should direct their query to ComplianceAmericas@barilla.com. If requested to remove data, we will respond within a reasonable timeframe.

Barilla will also provide an individual opt-out or opt-in choice before we share their Personal Information with third parties other than our agents, or before we use it for a purpose other than which it was originally collected or subsequently authorized. To limit the use and disclosure of your personal information, please submit a written request to ComplianceAmericas@barilla.com.

### Children and minors online privacy

Barilla complies with the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act (COPPA) which stipulates that Web site operators cannot knowingly collect personal information from children under age 13 without verifiable parental permission. Children are not eligible to use any of our services contained in this Site. We do not knowingly collect or use any personal information from users under 18 years of age. No information should be submitted to this Site by visitors under 18 years of age, and visitors under 18 years old are not allowed to register for our contests, newsletter, clubs or activities. You must be 18 years or older to use our services. If you are a minor, you can use our services only in conjunction with your parent or guardian and therefore you hereby agree and acknowledge that you are at least 18 years old or that a parent or guardian is supervising usage by, and is responsible for the actions of, any minor(s) who use your computer and/or account(s) to access the Barilla Website.

### Changes

Barilla reserves the right to change this Statement of Privacy at any time by notifying Barilla Website users of the existence of a new Privacy Policy or any updates by posting a notice at this location or by e-mail or by any other reasonable means.

### Contact information

Barilla welcomes your comments regarding this Statement of Privacy. If you believe that Barilla has not adhered to this Statement of Privacy, please visit our Contact Us page.
